If I feel good on one injection per two
weeks or one injection per week, is
there a medical long-term reason to
switch to more frequent injections like
twice per week? Yeah, it's interesting.
There's there's a little debate about
this in the community, right? You talk
to, you know, if you got a group of, you
know, us providers together, you'd hear
some hear some different, you know, some
different things about it. Um, I don't
think there's any great um literature or
research showing that there would be a
big difference. And I, you know, symptom
resolution is is is kind of king, too.
So, if you're feeling great, uh, you
know, why mess with it? Unless there's
something else bad going under the hood
that, you know, that that we're seeing.
Um, I do think most people seem to do a
little bit better with more frequent
injections. And even if they are feeling
good and don't notice anything
different, they might notice some
difference in some other parameters on
their blood work if they did change
change that kind of thing. Um, I I I
would say for the most part, if you're
feeling great, if if you're doing two
weeks, you know, one injection every two
weeks, there's no way you're not going
to have some improvements by going more
frequently. If you're feeling pretty
good at once a week injection, okay,
I'll I'll meet you there. I think that's
okay. Um, I think almost everyone does
better with two to three shots per week,
but as far as long-term health problems,
I mean, there's these are long acting
medications. The, you know, the
difference we're talking about is
probably not going to be a huge
difference. I know that's not uh not a
popular opinion with with everyone, but
uh yeah, somewhere between, you know,
three shots per week and maybe, you
know, ve very few folks will do okay
with, you know, with one and feel great
long term.
>> There there will be a consequence for
SHBG for sure if you only do once per
week.
>> Yeah. And I've seen and I'm hesitating
here too because I've seen some guys
where it doesn't seem to make a whole a
whole lot of difference and but it but
it it certainly can. It certainly can,
right? So, if you have someone who's,
you know, a high and and that might
adjust over time, too, depending upon
your lab. So, that's why it's important
to get some, you know, some uh some
comprehensive labs, see where the SBG is
going because things can change, right?
You start taking you start taking um an
exogenous hormone like testosterone,
it's going to start driving your SHBG
down, and now we might have to change
the protocol. So, maybe you started as
someone who, you know, who's actually
doing great with a less frequent
injection, but over time, you might, you
know, you might benefit as you as you
adjust things a little bit. Um, an SHBG
itself as a as a health marker is a is a
pretty interesting one, right? I mean,
you definitely don't want to see it
going too low. That's definitely a sign
of some bad things happening happening
metabolically. Uh, and then, you know,
higher can sometimes be better, but then
too high can be too high also. So, uh,
not not a number to chase. Something to
keep an eye on and definitely adjust as
you go. But if I'm starting off someone
fresh, I' i'd never start them at just
one injection per week. No, no way I'd
start them at two per week. Um, usually
I have them about three three times per
week.
>> Um, I'm sorry, I should say no way I
would do them, you know, once every two
weeks, not not two times per week. Most
of my guys started three injections per
week. Um, some of them, you know, some
of them do good with two. I think every
patient I have right now who's doing
once a week is someone who came to me
from somewhere else and has been doing
it for a long time and they feel great
and their labs look great and they don't
want to change anything. So, we just
leave it. But for for the most part, I
think more frequent is probably you're
probably just going to feel a little
better whether you know it or not.
>> Sure.